Ra'Fat A. AL-Msie'Deen

Curriculum Vitae



R.O. Box 61710, Mu'tah University, Alkarak - Jordan

00962795423410

✓ rafatals3ode@gmail.com

https://rafat66.github.io/Al-Msie-Deen/

in Linkedin

RafatALs3ode

PERSONAL DETAILS

Full Name Ra'fat Ahmad Ali AL–Msie'Deen

Nationality Jordanian
Place of Birth Tafila, Jordan
Marital Status Married

RESUME

My name is Ra'Fat Al-Msie'Deen and I am an Associate Professor at the faculty of information technology in the department of software engineering at the Mutah University, Al Karak – Jordan. I received my PhD in software engineering from the University of Montpellier 2, Montpellier – France, in 2014. I received my Master's degree in Information Technology from University Utara Malaysia, Kedah – Malaysia, in 2009. I got my B.Sc. in Computer Science from Al-Hussein Bin Talal University, Ma'an – Jordan, in 2007. I have several publications in international journals, conferences and books. I taught several courses in computer science and supervised several B.Sc. students.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science

June, 2014

University of Montpellier, Montpellier - France

Specialization: Software Engineering

TOPICS: Software Engineering and Software Product Line Engineering.

Master of Science - Information Technology

March, 2009

University Utara Malaysia, Kedah - Malaysia

Topics: Requirements Model, Systems Analysis and Design, and Advanced Programming.

GPA: 3.85/4

Bachelor of Computer Science

September, 2007

Al-Hussein Bin Talal University, Ma'an – Jordan

GPA: 72.94%

The General Secondary Education Certificate

August, 2004

Grandel Secondary School, Tafila - Jordan

Scientific Stream - GPA: 76.9%

MANAGERIAL EXPERIENCE

Head of the Department of CS

September, 2020 - September, 2021

Head of the Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Information Technology at Mutah University.

ACADEMIC AND TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Associate Professor

September 22, 2019 – Present

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

Taught Courses: Bachelor and Master Levels

<u>Bachelor level</u>: Software Engineering Fundamentals, Requirements Engineering, Software Documentation, Software Architecture and Design, Information Systems Management and Graduation Project.

Master Level: Advanced Software Engineering.

Assistant Professor

February 24, 2016 – September 22, 2019

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

Software Engineering, Computer Organization and Design, Introduction to Information Technology, Database Systems, Internet Programming, Special Topics In Computer Science, Communication Skills, Algorithms, Systems Analysis and Design, Theory of Computation, and Logic Circuits Design.

Full-Time Lecturer

September 22, 2014 – February 24, 2016

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

Decision Support Systems, Operating Systems, E-Commerce Programming, Computer Skills (I), and Computer skills (II) - Visual Basic.

Full-Time Lecturer

March, 2009 – December, 2011

Tafila Technical University, Tafila – Jordan

Taught Courses: Bachelor Level

Computer Graphics, Logic Circuits Design, Computer Skills (1), Computer Skills (2), International Computer Driving License "ICDL", Java Language, C++ Language, Database, Information Retrieval Systems, Management Information Systems, Internet Programming, Systems Analysis and Design, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, and Graduation project.

Part-Time Lecturer

September, 2010 – June, 2011

Arabian Education and Training Group, Amman – Jordan

Program Name: "High Diploma in Information and Communication Technologies in Education ICTE"

Taught Courses:

Web Design, Graphical Design, and Graduation project.

Teacher of Computer Science

October, 2007 - February, 2008

Ministry of Education, Tafila - Jordan

🗘 I taught computer science at Busira secondary school for boys, Busira - Jordan.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

- Chair of the postgraduate committee: Dept of CS at Mutah Univ (September, 2020 Sep., 2021).
- Member of MaREL team (Models and Reuse Engineering Languages) (January, 2012 April, 2014).
- Member of organization committee for the ECOOP, ECSA and ECMFA conferences (July 1-5, 2013).

PHD DISSERTATION

Reverse Engineering Feature Models From Software Variants to Build Software Product Lines: RIVEPLINE Approach. (University of Montpellier, Montpellier - France)

MASTER THESIS

A Requirement Model of Local News WEB/ WAP Application for Rural Communities. (University Utara Malaysia, Kedah — Malaysia)

SCHOLARSHIPS

A scholarship by the JOSYLEEN PROJECT - ERASMUS MUNDUS ACTION 2 towards PhD in computer science during the period of 2012-2014, Montpellier - France

ACADEMIC REFEREE

Marianne Huchard	Universitè de Montpellier @ Montpellier - France.
Wan Osman	Universiti Utara Malaysia @ Kedah - Malaysia.
Christelle URTADO	LGI2P/Ecole des Mines d'Alès @ Nîmes - France.

SKILLS

Languages	Arabic (mother tongue), English (reading, writing and conversation).
Certificates	International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL: UN07097892).
Programming Languages	Java, Python, C++, HTML, Java Script, Oracle, ASP.NET, PHP.
Software engineer skills	Teamwork, Communication skills, Leadership, Problem solving,
Workshops	Jordan Instructional Design Workshop - 2019.
	Workshop on Model-based Systems for Industrial Applications - 2008.
Software	Matlab, LATEX, Director, DreamWeaver, Photoshop,

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Software Engineering, Software Product Line Engineering (SPLE), Requirements Engineering, Formal Concept Analysis (FCA), Software Documentation, Software Visualization, and Feature Location in Source Code.

PUBLICATIONS

Publications Scopus Publons DBLP Google Scholar Research Gate

Journal:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Blasi, and Mohammed Alsuwaiket, "Constructing a Software Requirements Specification and Design for Electronic IT News Magazine System," *International Journal of Advanced and Applied Sciences*, vol. 0, no. 0, pp. 0–0, 2021.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, "SoftCloud: A Tool for Visualizing Software Artifacts as Tag Clouds," Mu'tah Lil-Buḥūth wad-Dirāsāt; Natural and Applied Sciences Series, vol. 0, no. 0, pp. 0–0, 2021.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "Software Evolution Understanding: Automatic Extraction of Software Identifiers Map for Object-Oriented Software Systems," *Journal of Communications Software and Systems*, vol. 17, no. 1, pp. 20–28, 2021.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Tag Clouds for Software Documents Visualization," *International Journal on Informatics Visualization*, vol. 3, no. 4, pp. 361–364, 2019.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Tag Clouds for Object-Oriented Source Code Visualization," *Engineering*, *Technology & Applied Science Research*, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 4243–4248, 2019.
- [6] Mohammed Alsuwaiket, A. Blasi, and R. Al-Msie'deen, "Formulating Module Assessment for Improved Academic Performance Predictability in Higher Education," Engineering, Technology & Applied Science Research, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 4287–4291, 2019.
- [7] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "Supporting software documentation with source code summarization," *International Journal of Advanced and Applied Sciences*, vol. 6, no. 1, pp. 59–67, 2019.
- [8] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "The Impact of the Object-Oriented Software Evolution on Software Metrics: The Iris Approach," *Indian Journal of Science and Technology*, vol. 11, no. 8, pp. 1–8, 2018.
- [9] <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Automatic labeling of the object-oriented source code: The Lotus approach," *Science International-Lahore*, vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 45–48, 2018.
- [10] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Visualizing object-oriented software for understanding and documentation," *International Journal of Computer Science and Information Security*, vol. 13, no. 5, pp. 18–27, 2015.
- [11] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. Seriai, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Automatic documentation of [mined] feature implementations from source code elements and use-case diagrams with the REVPLINE approach," *International Journal of Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering*, vol. 24, no. 10, pp. 1413–1438, 2014.
- [12] A. M. Frijat and R. Al-Msie'deen "A requirement model of local news wap/web application for rural community," Advances in Computer Science and Engineering, vol. 4, no. 1, pp. 37–53, 2010.

Book:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, Object-oriented Software Documentation. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2019.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, and M. Huchard, Reengineering Software Product Variants Into Software Product Line: REVPLINE Approach. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [3] <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, A Requirement Model of Local News Application for Rural Communities: A New Model for Rural News. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, and C. Urtado, Reverse Engineering Feature Models. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, Feature Location in a Collection of Software Product Variants. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.

International Conference:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. Seriai, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Reverse engineering feature models from software configurations using formal concept analysis," in *Proceedings of the Eleventh International Conference on Concept Lattices and Their Applications, Košice, Slovakia, October 7-10, 2014.*, ser. CEUR Workshop Proceedings, K. Bertet and S. Rudolph, Eds., vol. 1252. CEUR-WS.org, 2014, pp. 95–106.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Documenting the mined feature implementations from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software product variants," in *The 26th International Conference on Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering, Hyatt Regency, Vancouver, BC, Canada, July 1-3, 2013.*, M. Reformat, Ed. Knowledge Systems Institute Graduate School, 2014, pp. 138–143.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Feature location in a collection of software product variants using formal concept analysis," in *Safe and Secure Software Reuse 13th International Conference on Software Reuse, ICSR 2013, Pisa, Italy, June 18-20. Proceedings*, ser. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, J. M. Favaro and M. Morisio, Eds., vol. 7925. Springer, 2013, pp. 302–307.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Mining features from the object-oriented source code of software variants by combining lexical and structural similarity," in *IEEE 14th International Conference on Information Reuse & Integration, IRI 2013, San Francisco, CA, USA, August 14-16, 2013.* IEEE, 2013, pp. 586–593.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Mining features from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software variants using formal concept analysis and latent semantic indexing," in *The 25th International Conference on Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering, Boston, MA, USA, June 27-29, 2013.* Knowledge Systems Institute Graduate School, 2013, pp. 244–249.
- [6] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. D. Seriai, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and A. Al-Khlifat, "Concept lattices: A representation space to structure software variability," in *Information and Communication* Systems (ICICS), 2014 5th International Conference on, Irbid, Jordan, April 2014, pp. 1–6.

International Workshop:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. D. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "An approach to recover feature models from object-oriented source code," in *Actes de la Journée Lignes de Produits* 2012, Lille, France, Novembre 2012, pp. 15–26.
- [2] <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, A. D. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Feature mining from a collection of software product variants," in *Actes de la Journées GDR GPL CIEL AFADL 2013*, Nancy, France, April 2013, pp. 1–2.
- [3] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Recovering traceability links between feature models and source code of product variants," in *Proceedings of the VARiability for You Workshop: Variability Modeling Made Useful for Everyone*, ser. VARY '12. New York, NY, USA: ACM, 2012, pp. 21–25.
- [4] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Identifying traceability links between product variants and their features," in *REVE'2013: 1st International workshop on Reverse Variability Engineering*, 2013, pp. 17–23.
- [5] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Genetic algorithms as recovering traceability links method between feature models and source code of product variants," in *Actes de la Journée Lignes de Produits 2012*, Lille, France, Novembre 2012, pp. 3–14.

Poster:

[1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "A methodology to recover feature models from object-oriented source code," Innsbruck, Austria, September 2012.

Doctoral Symposium:

[1] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Mining feature models from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software product variants," in *Doctoral Symposium of ECOOP'13*, Montpellier, France, July 2013, pp. 1–10.

Dr. Ra'Fat A. AL-Msie'Deen 🎓 P.O. Box 61710, Mu'tah University, Alkarak - Jordan

 Image: Property of the propert